Hello, everyone. I'm Evelyn, a 3D designer and trainer from Clou, Shanghai.
Today is my first time to meet you in the studio.
Today's live stream is about wedding dresses.
Wedding dresses are divided into two parts.
In the upper part, I will show you how to make a wedding dress.
It will involve different production points.
I hope you can learn new knowledge by watching this live stream.
Since there are many simulation parts in this live stream,
I will show you how to record the video in advance.
Let's start the live stream.
First of all, let's take a look at the software version of Clou 6.1.
As you can see, many of our tools are hidden.
To make it easier for us to make, let's go to the settings.
Click on the user name.
Click on the user interface.
Change the position of the tool bar to the left and right.
Then turn off the tool selection.
Now you can see that most of our tools are displayed.
The virtual model used in this live stream is adjusted by Grace in our library.
Clou 6.1 also has a new function to make the model wear makeup and adjust skin color.
You can look forward to the live stream of Clou 6.1.
When we make a wedding dress, our production logic is very, very important.
When it comes to this kind of large and multi-layer complex structure clothing,
we must make it from the top to the bottom, from the internal support structure to the outer layer, layer by layer.
Every time we start the creation and production of a new layer,
we must make sure that the previous layer of production and simulation is in a stable state,
and then proceed to the next step of production.
The production logic of this live stream is also like this.
First, we can start to make the top.
This step can be understood as making money in 3D.
The tool used is our 3D pen virtual model.
We can enter a number here,
初时 could看到也能查看
我们先来绘制一下我们礼服内部支撑的鱼骨数音的结构
那我们先来绘制一下我们礼服内部支撑的鱼骨数音的结构
绘制好了以后
我们可以添加3D的分割线
来区分不同的是被版片
完成以后
Use the Flatten tool to flatten the 3D line we just drew into a 2D version.
After creating the version, make sure to arrange them in the 2D window,
in order to avoid confusion in the next production.
I have deleted the previous line,
and now I am going to edit the version and the sewing line.
At the same time, we need to clone the version.
Next, we need to check the version.
We need to make sure that the version we created is the same length as the one we created.
Here, I have used the Flatten tool and the Flatten tool.
Adjust the position of the flange to the same length.
Make sure there is not much difference between the length of the flange.
Use the rectangle tool.
Make sure there is not much difference between the length of the flange and the width of the flange.
The width of the flange is 1cm.
The height of the flange is the length of the sewing line.
After we are done,
we are going to make sure that the flange is placed on the other side of the flange.
Next, we are going to freeze the flange.
Then, we are going to sew the flange.
Next, we are going to make sure that the flange is in the 3D window.
Adjust the position of the flange.
The flange is in the 3D window.
To sew the flange and the UI version together,
we need to use the internal sewing line.
Choose the two sides of the flange
and add a 5mm internal sewing line.
Choose the two sides of the flange.
Add a 5mm internal sewing line.
After finishing, we can quickly sew it together.
After sewing, we can quickly arrange it by adding it to the outside.
After this, we can stitch it to the outside.
For more firmness and support, we can make a fabric in the frame.
Note that in CLO, the meaning of the name is English or Pinyin.
We can see that the name of the fabric is called Cloth.
I temporarily set our physical attribute to Trim Hardware.
After learning how to make an unchangeable physical attribute,
we can go back here and use the defined physical attribute fabric
to modify and replace it.
Put our fabric on our fishbone.
We can see that we used the default fabric on the number 1,
so it's a bit loose.
In fact, the number 1 top and bottom lines
are usually supported by the fishbone.
Therefore, we choose the top and bottom panel lines.
We add a sticky strip to support this part of the structure.
After completion,
we can modify it and freeze it.
Let's move on to the next part of the production.
Because we start from the beginning,
there is no conflict between the upper body and the lower body
in the process of making our clothes.
Therefore,
we start to make the upper body of the dress.
First,
I come to the window of my 2D version.
In the menu,
I display the texture surface of my 2D version window
and change it to the display method of Translucent Surface.
Then,
we can put our number 1 version
through a point-to-connection point
and put it together.
Then,
we can put our number 1 version
through a point-to-connection point and put it together.
Next,
we use our original measurement clothing tool
to determine the position of our line.
Then,
we use our editorial measurement clothing tool
to hook it as an internal line.
After we determine the position of our line,
we use the rectangular plate tool.
We can freely draw a rectangular plate
on top of the plate
and adjust its position.
Then,
we adjust its position.
we do this logic
on the display of the 2D version window,
such as Translucent Surface.
.
You can select information talking with you
from the window of this 2D version
and hook it to the burrow.
Next,
through the
point-to-connection point,
choose your ¡judı dia
As you can see, we didn't include all the front and back lines here.
Our square and rectangle panels didn't include them.
So here we need to use our internal multidirectional line tool to draw it out.
Then we will do the same for the back panel.
We will use the same method to draw the back panel.
After we are done, we will re-arrange the panels in the 2D window.
We can add more panels if we want.
For example, we can add more panels if we want in the 2D window.
Then we will add more panels if we want.
We can add more panels if we want.
and connect it to the other internal line
Then delete the part we don't need
You can see that some points are empty points
Let's adjust the path first
You can also adjust the curve
Then we can connect the points
To form a closed point
After checking
Then we can connect the points to a closed point
Then we can cut it off
Now we use the same method on the back
To build a closed line
During this process
I can add some volume to it
Then adjust it to its position and so on
After we have a closed internal shape
Let me check if there is a new point
Then we can cut it off
Then select the unnecessary part and delete it
Then re-arrange our panels according to our production logic in the 2D panel window
I recommend that you can
Create this
It's a good habit
Then we can quickly sew up the upper body
And use our 1 to n free sewing tool
To put our outer layer and inner layer
Together
Then pay attention to the place where we fold the sewing
We need to change the type of sewing thread
Change to Turned
After sewing, open the arrangement
Arrange and simulate it
In order to prevent accidents in the following operations
Here I will save my project file first
Then we can start the production of the lower half of our clothes
The production of the clothes
According to the previous process, we can start the production of the lower half of our clothes
According to the previous production logic
We first need to make the name of our wedding dress
This is what many of our friends are looking forward to
The most important part of this wedding dress production live broadcast
In the making of the name of the wedding dress in CLOUD
There are actually many different ways
Due to the time
I will talk about two different ways of making it
These two ways each has its own interests and its own challenges
These two ways each has its own strengths and weaknesses
to bemean the perspective of well worn clothes
Then after learning
When making, you can tune that smell
So, let's timbrelize
Then after learning
We need ruh
Our beautifulitz
we need ruh
are very important
our beautifulitz
They need only one girl
First of all, we need to arrange the
waist belt at the point of arrangement of the waist.
As you can see, our group name is relatively large, and the number of pieces is relatively large.
Therefore, it is obviously unrealistic to arrange it at the point of arrangement of the legs as usual.
Therefore, we need to use our positioning ball tool to arrange it in the state of closed simulation.
What I am using is the positioning ball of the screen coordinate, so I always switch to the right angle.
Like the front, back, side and top to arrange it.
OK, let's go to the next step.
When I arrange this step, I ensure that my plates are always arranged at the most accurate and nearest M.
At the end, I directly use the positioning feature like an arrow on the top of our positioning ball.
During our assessment, we use it for the position of the picot.
Next, we use our positioning ball.
Adjust the position of the panel.
Click on the position.
Set the position of the panel.
Then start the arrangement.
After the arrangement, I will freeze the panel part.
I finished sewing and simulation of the belt.
The reason why we made it in this way is that
in order to avoid the instability and unnecessary conflicts
when we simulate with multiple large panels,
we select each panel and sew it.
And pay attention, we simulate it independently.
In this way, we can reduce the computer's computing power
when we simulate single times.
You can try it yourself when you practice.
In this way,
we can reduce the computer's computing power
when we simulate single times.
So, it's a simple and easy way.
Although it looks troublesome now,
but in the long run,
it can improve the overall production efficiency of us.
This is the big panel we made.
Next, let's start
This method is relatively simple and rough.
Then we select our group name and group layout.
Come to our attribute editor.
Adjust the pressure to 1.
Then open the simulation.
You can see that our group name has been listed in history.
You can see that the advantage of this method is that it is very, very simple to make.
And our group layout can be moved along with our pull.
This method is very suitable for us to make wedding dresses.
It's not all-purpose, it's also a disadvantage.
The disadvantage is that the type of group name in this way is relatively monotonous.
We can only use it in medium-sized group names.
If we make some more design-like bird-like names or very large-sized scattered names, etc.,
When you have learned it, you can restore it.
Now let's talk about our second way of making.
This way of making is to adjust the physical properties of the fabric,
so that our skirt will really become stiff,
so that it can withstand the repeated structure of the outer layer, and so on.
This method is more demanding than the previous one,
and requires a more thorough understanding of our physical properties.
Let me first create the fabric that we need to use, and name it.
Next, let's go to our property editor.
Click on the physical properties.
We can see that the first thing we can see is the strength of our silk thread,
and the tension of our corner line.
This value controls the stretch of our fabric.
Let's skip it for now.
Let's go to our bending strength.
The bending strength is actually controlled by the hardness of our fabric.
The larger the value,
the harder it is to bend.
The harder the fabric is to bend,
the smaller the value,
the more the fabric feels.
Now let's adjust the strength to the maximum.
Let me show you how.
Next, let's look at the bending strength.
The bending strength is the opposite of the strength of our fabric.
It's a percentage.
This percentage determines the strength of our fabric.
Now look at the bending strength of our fabric.
Our fabric is easily bend,
and it's more likely that the bending strength of our fabric Seoul
will be inside the curve.
Now let's be case by case and write this exactly 0 as the bending strength.
Now, let's look at the strength.
The strength of our deformation determines the bending of each fold of our object.
The larger the strength of our deformation, the more difficult it is for the fold of the fabric to bend.
The smaller the number, the easier it is to bend.
This number needs to be set together with our bending strength.
This number represents the fold details of our fabric.
When we make this number, we want it to be firm and not flattened.
So we set it to 100.
At this point, the bending strength of our fabric is 100% of the strength of our deformation.
Finally, let's go back to the end of the fabric.
The bending strength of our fabric is 100% of the strength of our deformation.
The more the number, the easier it is to stretch the fabric.
The smaller the number, the easier it is to stretch the fabric.
Here, because we have adjusted the hardness of our fabric to the maximum through a series of settings just now,
At this point, if our fabric is also very strong in stretching,
our fabric can't bend or stretch.
It will become like hard paper.
The effect of the bending strength of our fabric is relatively hard.
Therefore, in order to simulate the effect of the bending strength of our fabric,
we set the number to 30.
Then apply it to the fabric.
You can see that the bending strength of our fabric has changed.
When we simulate it,
because our fabric is relatively large,
the speed of the simulation will also be relatively slow.
We can adjust its shape by pulling the mouse.
Help it simulate.
Then you can see that after our simulation is stabilized,
it has made a very, very round group.
It has made a very, very round group.
Then this kind of approach has the advantage of being very stable.
Then we can adjust our physical property.
The effect of this method can be applied to any type of purification.
Including the why-not structure that we mentioned before
like New uh
It's also a defect.
Its disadvantage is that when it's on sale,
it looks more businesslike than the pressure method.
So this method is more suitable for us to do static effects.
Here, I will open it and talk about the external words.
Previously, I saw one of our Shenzhen students on our Closet Connect.
He made a blue dress before this live broadcast.
The way he used it is also very clever.
He made the particle diameter of the group to be very large.
It seems to be 500 or something.
The particle diameter is too large,
which leads to a state where the group is not able to bend at all.
Then use this method
to let us
support our group.
This is also a very smart method.
It can be seen that if we are familiar with
the various settings in our Clou software,
and its relevant usage,
when making clothes,
we have infinite possibilities.
Although I only told you two methods today,
I welcome you to explore other possibilities yourself.
I also invite you to leave us comments
and share your research results.
Next, we will start the production of the outer layer of the wedding dress.
Let's take a look at the size of the front waist first.
Let's build a rectangular plate.
The length of this plate,
we are currently adjusting according to the approximate.
Before continuing,
I will first freeze all the layers that I have done before.
Let's take a look.
I have extended it a little bit.
This may not be accurate.
This is adjusted according to our visual effect.
You can see that we have two extension tools.
One is the extension plate line,
and the other is the extension plate point.
Here, when we need to add the amount of extension evenly,
I used the extension plate line.
When we open and open the window,
I set the direction according to the direction of the arrow.
Then I entered the amount of extension.
It seems that we can make it bigger.
I want a larger group.
After that,
I pulled it out,
and then spread it out in a symmetrical way.
Then I froze it first.
I opened the simulation.
I want to make sure that the outer layer of our upper body is in a very suitable state.
Then I will use my positioning ball
to place and arrange it.
Then I will use my positioning ball to place and arrange it.
The arrangement of this arrangement is the same as before.
We need to place it as close to the seam to the simulation as possible.
But at the same time,
it will not be in a state of interlocking with other panels.
At the same time, it will not be in a state of interlocking with other panels.
Then when I simulate it,
I will put it in a position that is close to the seam.
Look here.
We could see that I used a hardener here.
This is to reduce the number of Load
I will stop the simulation when it is connected
Freeze it
Then, when I am making the back panel
I use the same method
Then, spread it out evenly
对称出来。
使用我们的定位工具,先快速定位,然后再进行安排。
安排的时候注意要板片和板片不要穿插,不然容易造成我们之后模拟的一个不稳定。
And then we will do the activation and simulation one by one.
After all is done,
I can pull our panels more evenly to separate the amount of our群摆
And then here you may notice my object window
I turned the car a little bit here
Because after we just finished making the群称
I forgot to change the fabric and started to build our new panels
So here I need to change the fabric of our群摆 to our default fabric
Apply
And then take a look
It's in different angles
It looks like the skirt is a little short now
At this time, I use
A tool called the panel extension tool
You can quickly make an extension
Then I know that in the end
The effect may be different
Then I'll do it first
Make an extension according to the approximate
Then continue
After I just finished
I first hardened it and then
After it has been simulated and stabilized
It's all frozen
Then I want to add a layer for it
A little shorter than it
A layer of outer mesh
Then we are here
I don't want to continue
I just extended the panel
That operation
The fastest way
Is to use our panel extension tool
Direct
Select our panel
Cut it to the outer layer
Pay attention
When we are using the panel extension tool
When creating panels
The panels created and the panels that are cut
Are sewn together
So we need
Use the editing sewing tool
Delete the seam line
Then remove the joint
Then next
In order to shorten this outer mesh
I used our editing panel
The internal line of the tool
To make it easier to sew
I used a 3D window
To check its effect
Then cut it off
And sew it quickly
The waistline part
Is still related to its bottom layer
It's a folding relationship
Remember
So
Every time we have a fold
Remember to change the seam line type
To Turn
Now you can see
The state of our grid
Is through our series of editing operations
Every time we edit
In fact, our grid
Is being reorganized
So now there are some holes
In the grid
So before we start the simulation
I'll go to the attribute editor
Change the layer of our outer mesh
From 0 to 1
And then start the simulation
The default layer is 0
If I want it
To add a layer outside
Change it to
A value greater than 0
Inside
It's a value greater than 0
Then adjust
Remember
When the simulation is stable
Once the layer is stable
After the
We must change it back to 0
Finally, let's look at my wedding dress. I think it's a little bit monotonous.
I want to add a harmony to it. A design with a living person.
What about the way? I'll start with this rope.
It is also to build a rectangular board first.
I set the height to 50 centimeters.
Because I know that I will adjust it later.
First of all,
Let's make it a one-sided effect.
Use our extension board to cut it first.
Extend it.
Don't make it too big.
Because we still need to adjust the part where we need to make a living person.
Because I want it to be more exaggerated.
More sense of design.
So I adjust it to a design like this.
We talked about it before.
We have two extension tools.
In order to make a bigger living person in a specific place.
At this time, we need to use our extension board.
The line tool for operation.
Extend board point. Sorry.
Then we choose every location for a living person.
Extend it.
I think we need to add.
Maybe.
3 to 4 living people.
That's enough.
Then you can see this.
As you can see, the live version is not very smooth.
So we can select these straight lines and convert them to free lines.
Next, I'll use our editor to adjust it.
Then come to the editor tool.
I've deleted all the unnecessary straight lines.
As you can see, in the process of deleting,
the curve of the live version is becoming smoother.
After that, we can arrange it.
In this process, you can see that every time I do the adjustment,
I always switch it to a straight view.
Like just now, it's straight up, and then look at it from different angles,
and then adjust the angle in front of it.
After that, we can seal it.
And then we can print it, and then we can set the level.
The level setting here is for the stability of the simulation.
Because the live version is printed now,
so the level of the light is not very obvious.
I've used the fixer tool.
I'm going to adjust its shape.
When I adjust the back side,
I pay attention to the back of the line.
Don't let it float to the other side.
Otherwise, after we align the board,
the amount in the back is very easy to penetrate,
causing instability.
After completing this simulation,
we align it again.
The reason for doing this operation is because
after we adjust the shape,
we can see that it's still the same shape in the 3D window.
In this way, we can save time on the other side
to simulate and adjust the live version.
After completion, delete the fixer.
And then,
the level is also modified to be normal.
To simulate.
We're done with this part.
Because I want to show it to you,
I'm going to add a new layer to it.
Because I want to make it like in many high-end clothes.
The lace fabric is on the outside of the cross section.
So, I'm going to add a Cologne layer here.
Then,
after adding it,
I'm going to add the bottom layer,
which is our original board,
a plate,
a frozen column,
and then,
a layer for our outer layer.
In order to make our simulation smoother,
easier to penetrate.
When we are done, let's see if there is a bump on the edge.
Wait for the simulation to be stable.
After the simulation is stable, we can adjust the level again.
Don't forget the other side.
Finally, let's see if there is a bump on the edge.
Finally, we need to check the overall shape of our wedding dress.
Is it still a little short in the front?
So what's next?
I'll freeze the part I just made.
And then I'll use our panel line expansion tool.
And then I'll add a panel line expansion tool to the front.
And then I'll add a panel line expansion tool to the back.
After that, I'll do a simulation of each panel.
After that, I'll add a panel line expansion tool to the front.
You can see that although we are doing a single-layer simulation,
it still has a relatively large movement at the beginning.
If we don't do a single-layer simulation, it's easy to make mistakes.
You can see that I just made a little bit of a hole.
So at this point, I'll remove the top panels.
And then I'll do a simulation.
Here is the result.
The butt of this dress is not very nice.
but we'll make some adjustments later.
At this point, the wedding dress is ready to go.
Now we can apply a suitable fabric in different parts of our wedding.
I'm in the window of my dummy room.
For the fabric, I searched for silk and added the three types of fabrics that we need.
The reason why I added these three types of fabrics is because the main body of our wedding dress is usually like this kind of fabric.
As for the outer fabric, I want it to have a certain width, so I added organza fabric.
As for the upper body of our wedding dress, we need a thin fabric with a wide width.
So we used a silk ribbon.
.
I've also unlocked the group name freeze.
You can see that when I start the simulation,
it has some penetrations.
So I'm going to go from the inside to the outside
and give it a layer setting.
I'm going to set the penetrations for each layer.
The inner layer is small and the outer layer is large.
Let's wait for it to go in.
When the layer is simulated,
after the simulation is stable,
we need to adjust the layers.
In the previous operation,
I've already activated the group name.
You can see that the group name of the hard drive
that we adjusted with physical properties
can support the outer layer
and layer by layer in the state of simulation.
Next, let's check the shape of the clothing
and some of the details of the production.
Let's turn around and see.
Now we can see that some parts of the skirt
have been folded up.
And then,
because we've adjusted the length of the sheet,
we need to adjust the length of the skirt.
So we need to adjust the sewing line accordingly.
When we make the bottom of the skirt,
in fact,
we usually have a support structure
similar to the one of the woolen skirt
on the edge of our skirt.
So we need to adjust the width of the skirt.
Here,
in the 6.1 version,
the width of the seam allowance
can be set to the maximum 5cm.
When we simulate,
we select our seam allowance,
and add a seam allowance.
Set the width of the seam allowance.
The width is set to 5cm, and then choose a harder preset, and then simulate it.
You can see that our simulation is slower now that we've created a multi-layer structure.
Now that we've applied the new physical properties to the board,
we can simulate it.
We can simulate it.
To make it work faster, we can freeze a part of the board first,
and then harden it before the simulation,
to cut off the creases from the default material during the simulation,
and then speed up our simulation by dragging it.
This way we can easily pull out the creases that are hidden in the bottom.
We can also do the same for the sand.
After applying the new physical properties to the board,
Sometimes you will find that the process from one physical attribute to another physical attribute is a little bit slow.
At this time, we can first harden it.
Let's say, give it a support force and flatten it.
It's like opening it and brushing it.
It's like brushing our physical attribute.
After finishing this process,
when we cancel hardening and simulate it again,
we can simulate a real fabric effect in a relatively short time.
Thank you.
This part of the simulation is a little bit slow.
I will adjust it by pulling it.
Then different layers have to be simulated.
Then wait for it slowly.
In this process, we can turn off the things we don't want to show,
such as the 3D line we drew before,
and our sticky tape.
These displays can be turned off.
You can see that there are about four living things.
When we come to the next layer,
pay attention to our skirt.
Don't let it fold in our clothes.
Pull it out a little bit and simulate it again.
Next, we wait until...
I skipped a little bit,
because our simulation is relatively slow.
After we finish hardening,
we have to cancel hardening first.
Then wait for some time for our computer
to simulate the real fabric effect.
Next, we can
create our texture effect.
I choose our silk fabric
to the attribute side.
The texture attribute type is silk satin,
which is our fabric.
Then I increase its thickness a little bit,
because our Taf silk
is not that bright.
It's not as bright as silk satin
or silk satin.
Next, I want to apply the effect
of the lace on the silk fabric
on the upper body and the upper body of the wedding dress.
Here, based on my different needs,
I use two methods to make it.
When we are making the part of the living thing,
we have already made it in two layers before.
The reason for doing this is
because we need to show
the structure of the double-layer
lace and its flexibility.
But for the upper body,
as long as we can see the effect of the lace,
we can do it.
So now I add
the fabric of the upper body
and separate it.
Then I directly give the double-layer
fabric that we made before
the name of it is lace.
Then I add the double-layer
fabric.
I will add the lace afterwards.
Then on the upper body,
I use the print cloth function
to click to add the print cloth
and to add the lace pattern.
Then, at the same time,
to show the sense of discipline,
I applied a hairstyle sticker to it.
Increase the intensity
The lower layer is still silk satin
The outer layer is a matte finish
This is how we represent the lace blinds
The lower layer is already double layered
So we select the upper layer
And apply the lace pattern
This is a transparent background PNG image
The system has a function that automatically generates and detects stickers
I don't know if you have tried it
When we encounter a copper cloth
We can select it
It is very convenient to use our software
To automatically generate a hair line sticker
The method is to directly pull the intensity of the bottom of our hair line pattern to 100
And then adjust it
After I opened the high-quality rendering
I found that our lace pattern
Its attribute type is still cross-sided
So I'm going to come back
Change our lace pattern
Change it to matte
You can see
We probably have this
The lace is covered on the cross-section
This effect has already come out
We also need to apply our net sand pattern
Come directly to the attribute editor
Find our net sand pattern
To fill in its color
Because I used a black net sand pattern at the beginning
Change it to a more ivory-white color
You can also adjust the transparency
That's it
Our wedding dress live broadcast
The first half of the live broadcast
It's all over
Let's go to our rendering window
Take a look
This is the one we're currently making
Its approximate effect
Now this live broadcast
We only teach you
Created the structure of our wedding dress
Talked about our group name
Everyone knows that we are still
No details have been made yet
Then our details live broadcast
Like what headscarf
What flash diamond
All kinds of stickers
And so on
These
Part of the live broadcast
We put it in our wedding dress live broadcast
The second half of the live broadcast
Then on June 3
There is our new function live broadcast of 6.1
Then
The details of our wedding dress live broadcast live broadcast
The second half of the live broadcast
It is currently suspended in our June mid-autumn
We can see you then
Do we have any questions now?
I'm a little afraid to show them off
You can forward the question to us
If you have any questions
You can contact us
You can post it to us
If you don't have it, our live stream will end here.
As we just talked about, we will also have our new features live stream in June.
You can look forward to what new features our development team has made,
which are good and powerful.
At the same time, I also hope that when we do our next live stream,
you can say goodbye to everyone in the live stream room.
This live stream is my first live stream, so I'm a little nervous.
I hope you can tolerate me.
Let's end here.
See you next time.
Thank you.